socialcast.com 2014-12-01

# Privacy | Socialcast

## SOCIALCAST PRIVACY POLICY

 _Version 2.1 Effective June 5, 2012_

Thank you for visiting our website. We are committed to protecting our visitors' and members' privacy. The following Privacy Policy outlines the information Socialcast, Inc., a VMware company ("Socialcast" or the "Company") may collect and how we may use that information to better serve visitors and members.

This privacy statement describes how Socialcast collects and uses the personal information you provide on our Web sites: [www.socialcast.com](http://www.socialcast.com/) and [www.strides.do](http://www.strides.do/). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

Socialcast has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [ TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. This privacy statement covers the Web site [www.socialcast.com](http://www.socialcast.com/). TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact Michelle Horton at [hortonm@vmware.com](http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection#fa9295888e959497ba8c978d9b889fd4999597). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

Socialcast complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union and Switzerland. Socialcast has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor Program, and to view Socialcast's certification, please visit <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>.

BY USING OUR WEBSITE, YOU AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. Please review the following carefully so that you understand our privacy practices in regards to:

  * Children Under the Age of 13
  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use Your Information
  * Our Disclosure of Your Information
  * Security
  * Revisions and Amendments

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [support@socialcast.com](http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection#acdfd9dcdcc3ded8ecdfc3cfc5cdc0cfcddfd882cfc3c1) .

### Children Under the Age of 13

The Company cares about the safety of children. Since our content and services are not directed towards kids, children under 13 are not allowed to register with our website or to participate in public posting areas on our website. If a child under the age of 13 tries to register, they will be "bumped-out" of the registration process after entering their birth date. In the event that we discover we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13 without parental consent, the Company will delete that information as soon as possible.

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

Upon registration with the Company, a user profile is developed to further customize the user's experience. We collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number, Company Name
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name, account number, password

Once you use the service, we may also collect other information from you, if you provide such information while using the service. The information may include, but is not limited to:  
Demographic information such as age, education, job title, business unit, department, start date, usernames, application usage, gender, location, interests and zip code. Because user privacy is important to us, access to the raw user data is restricted within the Company to our data scientists and authorized employees. After the data is scrubbed of personally identifiable information, we use this information internally to analyze general usage patterns and determine how users are using different aspects of the service in order to improve it and provide a better experience to our members.

As is true of most Web sites, we automatically gather information about your computer such as your IP address, browser type, referring/exit pages, and operating system.

We use this information to:

  * Send you product, service, and new feature information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Respond to requests for pricing information
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Display content based upon your interests
  * Provide a customized experience
  * Send you newsletters and other promotional communications to enhance your experience with our products and services

We enable you to create a profile, and share information such as messages, photos, and videos with others. Please note that we cannot control the actions of others with whom you may choose to share your pages and information.

In addition, tracking information may be collected as you navigate through our site. To help us serve your needs better, we use "cookies" to store and sometimes track user information. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies can be disabled or controlled by setting a preference within your browser.

### How We Use Your Information

Among our primary goals in collecting information is to provide you with a customized experience when visiting our site and to make our site more valuable to you. We use this information to closely monitor which areas of the site are used most and to determine which areas we need to focus on improving. As indicated above, access to identifiable information is restricted, and information in aggregate form is used by the Company so that we may continue to improve the value of the services and information on our website for our members as a whole.

The Company uses your Internet Protocol (IP) address to help diagnose problems with our computer server, and to administer our web site (the "Website"). Your IP address is used to help identify you, and to gather broad demographic data. Your IP address contains no personal information about you.

Users of our website should be aware that non-personal information and data may also be automatically collected by virtue of the standard operation of the Company's computer servers or through the use of "cookies". Cookies are files a website can use to recognize repeat users, and allow a website to track web usage behavior. Cookies take up minimal room on your computer and cannot damage your computer's files. Cookies work by assigning a number to the user that has no meaning outside of the assigning website. Users should be aware that the Company cannot control the use of cookies (or the resulting information) by third-parties. If you do not want information to be collected through the use of cookies, your browser allows you to deny or accept the use of cookies. There may, however, be some features on the website which require the use of cookies in order to customize the delivery of information to you.

### Information Sharing

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. The Company does not sell or rent personal information about its customers to any third parties. In the event the Company does engage in such commerce in the future, notice will be given and you will have an opportunity to remove yourself from any such lists prior to your inclusion therein by emailing us at [support@socialcast.com](http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection#23505653534c515763504c404a424f404250570d404c4e). The Company may, however, perform statistical analysis of customer usage in order to measure interest in, and use of, the various parts of the Website, and the Company may share that information in the course of its business, but such shared information shall be in aggregated form only (statistics, etc.), and will contain no personally identifiable information whatsoever.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services that help us with our business activities such as offering customer service or sending out emails on our behalf. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information:  
as required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;  
when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;  
if Socialcast is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information;  
to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

The Company cooperates with all law enforcement inquires and with all third parties to enforce their intellectual property or other rights.

You should be aware that if you voluntarily disclose personal information in public chat areas, on public bulletin boards, or in public classified advertisement areas within the Website, that information might be collected and disseminated by third-parties, and result in, among other things, unsolicited inquiries, messages, and offers from third-parties. Please understand that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and this third-party conduct is out of the control of the Company. Please also be aware that if you voluntarily disclose personal information in private chat areas, on private bulletin boards, or in private classified advertisement areas within the Website, all users who are authorized to access such areas will have access to such personal information, and that information might be collected and disseminated by those users, and result in, among other things, unsolicited inquiries, messages, and offers from such users. The Company urges you to please exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information on the Website, in either public or private areas of the Website.

This Website may also contain links to other websites. The Company is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third party websites.

### Choice / Opt-Out

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication.

### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

We may use cookies, for example, to keep track of your preferences and profile information. Cookies are also used to collect general usage and volume statistical information that does not include personal information.

We use another company to place cookies on your computer to collect non-personally identifiable information to compile aggregated statistics for us about visitors to our site.

### Web beacons

Our Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.

### Links to Other Websites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Socialcast. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit.

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. We cannot guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that information you supply won't be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet, and any information you transmit to the Company you do at your own risk. We recommend that you not disclose your password to anyone.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [support@socialcast.com](http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection#1d6e686d6d726f695d6e727e747c717e7c6e69337e7270).

### Additional Policy Information

Our Web site may include Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

Our Web site may offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@socialcast.com](http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection#cab9bfbabaa5b8be8ab9a5a9a3aba6a9abb9bee4a9a5a7). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### Surveys

From time-to-time we may use your information to contact you to complete surveys that we use for marketing and quality assurance purposes. We may use a third party service providers to conduct these surveys on our behalf; that company is prohibited from using our customers' personally identifiable information for any other purpose.

### Updating / Accessing / Amending / Correcting Personally Identifiable Information

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete or remove information by making the change on our member information page, emailing our Customer Support at [support@socialcast.com](http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection#ddaea8adadb2afa99daeb2beb4bcb1bebcaea9f3beb2b0) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within 5 business days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [support@socialcast.com](http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection#8ffcfaffffe0fdfbcffce0ece6eee3eceefcfba1ece0e2). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Notification of Privacy Statement Changes

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. This Privacy Policy is effective as of June 5, 2012. This Privacy Policy is not intended to, and does not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.

### Contact Information

You can contact us by writing or email us at the address below:  
Socialcast by VMware  
501 2nd Street, 7th Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94107

Email: [support@socialcast.com](http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection#d9aaaca9a9b6abad99aab6bab0b8b5bab8aaadf7bab6b4).
